Hi and welcome to this session on what's
new in financial management.
The topic is consolidation improvements
for this release.
My name is Brian Nielsen. I'm a program
manager in the Business Central team and
with me I have Joshua who's an engineer
in the same team.
And we will demonstrate some of the new
capabilities.
In consolidation
um we have focused on
improvements that will help you manage
currencies when you're doing
consolidation.
In order to do so, we have introduced a
consolidation status list so you can see
what have
already happened.
Um you'll be able to while you're in the
process of
uh executing consolidation, you will be
able to look up currency exchange rate
and maybe modify them.
So it fits with with what you're
currently doing.
Um if you're recovering from mistakes
uh you will be able to look up the last
closing
rate
uh while you're also doing uh
consolidation. So that helps you
enormously when you're trying to do
recovery.
And then in the whole process we have
introduced some validation so you don't
accidentally make mistakes. Uh
consolidation is a a tricky thing.
Um
but Joshua will uh take you through uh
consolidation. We have a setup where we
have one consolidation company and we
have two subsidiaries. And um
Joshua, if you can run consolidation for
February in this company.
Yeah, sure. So as Brian said, we have
here uh
consolidation company.
And I have two business units.
One in USD dollars and one in euros.
So we have now this consolidation runs
status and we have we can see now that
we have run this twice before.
One for January for each of the business
units and we can also see which
companies were running each
consolidation. Here we see that both
were but here we had an error for
example. And we can see what was the
error.
Right? In this case we forgot to set up
the exchange rate losses account but now
I have done that and we can run it
again.
Okay, so now let's consolidate this
business units for the next period for
February.
So we can set the starting and ending
date, document number and so on.
Select the companies that we want to
consolidate. We added this last
consolidation ending date so whenever
you consolidate it will show up here the
date that you did that
in.
And then you can configure the exchange
rates.
So
yeah, let's have a look at
how that looks.
So whenever you click one of these, you
will be shown
the
the things that you would configure
usually in the business unit card, you
can configure them now here.
And you can set the average currency
factor whenever when you have a
consolidation you want to specify two
different currency factors, the ones
that you use for your balance sheet
which is the closing currency factor and
the ones that you use for your income
statement which is the average currency
factor.
And the last closing currency factor is
usually set by the last run. So in this
case, it was the one we did on January.
So
this is all good. This is automatically
set when you run a consolidation.
We can see it here if we go to exchange
rates and we see that for February we
need an exchange rate of 1 to 1 to 4.
So
we can verify that that is the case here
and it's all good.
So, let's go ahead and
run the consolidation.
And that's it.
So, now we can see, if we go to our
financial report that we have prepared
for consolidation,
that the data for
the month of February
is
uh properly extracted from the
subsidiaries.
Okay. Thank you, Joshua. So,
consolidation with currencies is a lot
easier in this release.
You have a list of uh status from
previous runs, so you can see what has
been performed. You can dig into details
on that.
When you're doing consolidation, you can
actually change the exchange rate being
used while you're in the process of
doing the consolidation.
You'll be able to look up the rates. Uh
you can change them.
And we put in some validation, so you
don't accidentally
uh start running a consolidation for
something you have already done
consolidation for.
This is all good.
Um but mistakes still happen sometimes
for various reasons.
Let's say that in our two companies, we
have discovered a a small mistake, and
we really want to redo February. We have
done March already, and now we want to
do quality reporting, but we discovered
that there was a small mistake in the
data
from one of the companies.
So, we want to redo February and March.
And that is sometimes a tricky process
because when you're doing consolidation
on balance sheet items, you need to
revalue the balance from the previous
period. And you know, in order to do
that correctly, you need to know
what closing rate has been used in the
previous run. And when you're going back
in time and trying to redo stuff,
uh it's sometimes hard to remember what
rate was used. You can see it from the
the different entries, but they are
using the reciprocal value.
Uh, so we thought, let's let's just help
you with with picking the right rate and
and moving forward faster. So, um
we made a mistake. Joshua, can you
recover and redo February and maybe also
March again?
Sure. So, as Brian said,
um
I have already
uh configured the consolidation for
March and I already performed it. Here
Here you can see it.
But, there was a mistake in February and
we want to re-import.
So, how should we go ahead and do that?
So, if we consolidate
and we want to say that we want to do
the month of February,
it will by default, if you notice, not
select this because it detects that you
have already consolidated these
companies. But, if you want to do so,
then you can, which is the case because
we want to rerun for this company.
And it also tells you that the last
consolidation ending date is in March.
So, you have to be aware.
And now, when we want to configure the
currency exchange rates, it will show
you this warning saying that you have
already drawn this
uh for this period. So, you can select
from previous consolidations
the currency exchange rates that you
have used. As Brian said, the
exchange rates were okay. It was just
that there was some missing data. So, we
just want to rerun that.
So, we can just select this currency
exchange rates that we used back in
February. And here is a list of the
previous exchange rates. It doesn't show
the ones from March because that one was
not used back then.
So, you can choose which one which
exchange rates to use. So, we can see
that in February we we used these
exchange rates.
And you can select which exchange rates
do you want to transfer from there. In
this case, we want all because they were
all okay.
And the last closing currency factor is
the one corresponding to the period of
January, and that will make the entries
the adjustment entries of the on the
balance accounts to be correct.
So, okay.
Let's say okay.
And
Yeah.
That's it. So, now you will go ahead and
see the financial report.
And this is the totals for a balance
sheet account, for example, and we can
drill down and see what entries do we
have here.
So, these two entries are the ones that
get invalidated after the rerun is done.
Here is the transferred from the
business unit with the corresponding
exchange rates.
And this is the adjustment done due to
the different uh reruns that we have
done.
Thank you, Joshua.
So, with this release, we've made some
improvements to manage currencies during
consolidation, and we also added uh a
small capability to look up previous
runs and select the rates that were
used, either all of them or selectively,
so that recovering from mistakes during
consolidation uh is an easier task.
We will make a few more improvements
over the next one or two releases to
make it an even smoother process, giving
you more overview.
Um but in the meantime, if you have
feedback, you can of course contact us
in uh various ways, but I would always
uh emphasize, if you have ideas for
improvements to the product, go to BC
Ideas and submit or vote on other
people's ideas. Thank you for joining
this session.